Devang Oza

Flat No. – 4, Punitnagar Shopping Centre
Nr. Punitnagar – 1, Umiyavijay ,
Satellite Road, Ahmedabad 380015 ,
Gujarat, India.
Mobile +91 9586164030
Email- devoze2003@gmail.com

About me and brief overview :-

Results-driven sales manager having extensive career in sales of various building materials. Familiar with diverse promotions, events, networking, and business development. Able at developing productive relationships with local builders, specifiers, and dealers.

- ✓ More than fifteen years of experience in sales of building materials.
- ✓ Experience of working with well-known professionally managed companies with reputed brands in the sector.
- ✓ Demonstrated track record of successfully carrying out sales, marketing and business development tasks.
- ✓ Conversant with Institutional (Project) sales and Channel (Retail) sales.

Education

 Diploma In Plastics Engineering Govt Polytechnic Ahmedabad, Gujarat

Bachelor in Business Administration (BBA)
 Sikkim Manipal University, Distance education

Skills
 Languages – English , Hindi , Gujarati
 MS office and internet application proficiency

Completed in 1999 75 % Marks

Completed in 2014 75 % Marks

CRM Knowledge – Salesforce Basic knowledge of Accounts



Birthdate: 12, November 1978

Nationality: Indian

Gender : Male

Marital status: Married



Work Experience

1) SAPA BS India Pvt Ltd

Since September 2019 till present Area Sales Manager - Gujarat

"Technal" is an international brand for Aluminum system windows and façade of Hydro group Europe. The company is one of the leading innovators globally for high performance façade solutions and durable Aluminum window systems.

Job profile and responsibilities -

- > Overall responsibility of sales, technical coordination and receivables for Gujarat.
- > Sales include Projects, institutional sales and premium retail sales at villas etc.
- Business development by specifications through architects and PMC
- Addition of new fabricator partners and showrooms.

2) RAK Ceramics (I) Pvt Ltd -

April 2018 – August 2019 Sales Manager, Sanitary ware – Gujarat

RAK ceramics is a reputed MNC in India in ceramic industry. RAK is a leading manufacturer of ceramic tiles, vitrified tiles & Sanitaryware's. RAK showcases its product range through its company showrooms and extensive dealer outlets PAN India.

Job profile and responsibilities -

- Handling sales and other operations for RAK sanitaryware in Gujarat for Project and Channel sales.
- Handling and guiding team of sales persons.

3) Dorset Kaba Security Systems Pvt Ltd

March 2013 to April 2018 Deputy manager, Institutional Sales – Gujarat

"Dorset" was a joint venture between Kaba – Switzerland and Dorset group of India. Dorset is one of the largest manufacturers of locking systems and architectural hardware products. The company also markets electronic locks, access control systems & other construction hardware. It has been awarded with Powerbrand and Super-brand awards.

Job profile and responsibilities -

- Generate sales from Developers, Government project and Institutional projects
- Close contact with architects and specifiers for approvals.
- Effective implementation of company policies and manage receivables.
- Provide installation, technical guidance and handle aftersales service.
- Coordination with dealers, distributors and channel partners.
- > Handling team of salesperson .

4) Wipro Enterprises P Ltd . (Electrical Wiring Products-)

June 2010 to March 2013 Area Sales Executive - Ahmedabad

"Wipro" is a well known company and an Indian MNC. It is a diverse group having presence in FMCG, Lighting, Furniture & electricals. Served Wipro in modular switches and wiring devices division with brand name "NORTH-WEST". It products range was premium modular switches, MCB, Distribution products. IT also had some value added products like IR based scene controller and standalone security system etc.

Job profile and responsibilities -

- Sales & marketing of premium modular switches, Distribution board & other wiring devices in the area of Ahmedabad & North Gujarat.
- \blacktriangleright Generate sales from Builders , Architects , Govt. & Institutional projects. \neg Develop retail sales network in the area .
- To establish & develop new channel Stockists & retailers.
- ➤ Handle a team of Sales promoters and lead them to achieve defined objectives.
- Arrange and handle promotional activity like Electrician meets, exhibitions, ensure effective merchandising.

5) Finolex Industries Ltd. (Pipes Division)

Aug 2006 to June 2010 Sales Executive - Ahmedabad

One of the Super brand in PVC Pipes and fitting segment and a well known company . It is largest manufacturer of PVC pipes with backward integration to PVC resin manufacturing . Commitment towards quality is the core value of the company . As a necessity PVC pipes are used vastly in various sectors like infrastructure , real estate development , irrigation etc . Finolex had its regional offices across the country and manufacturing facilities at Maharashtra and Gujarat .

Job profile and responsibilities -

- Sales & marketing of PVC pipes & fittings in the region of Ahmedabad & North Gujarat
- Develop retail dealer network in the area and increase retail sales .
- Generate sales from builders, industrial projects and Govt. Projects in the area.
- Arrange promotional activity like mason meets, participation in exhibition, events, Factory visits etc.
- Increase awareness about Full product range among Architects, Engineers & Contractors.
- Handling of Dealer sales team & guide them for better sales.

6) Pidilite Industries Ltd.

(Construction Chemicals Div., ROFF - Retail)

March2005 to Aug2006 Territory Sales In charge - Ahmedabad

"Pidilite" - a well known company for its legendary brands. It's an innovative company in terms of product development, product portfolio and unique marketing style. Admirable strength of the company is its ability to create vast market for its products and then capture a leading market share. The company has a detailed and in-depth approach for customer and sales data beginning from ground level. Construction chemicals is one of the business unit of Pidilite with brands like Dr Fixit and Roff.

Job profile and responsibilities -

- ➤ Handling sales of "ROFF" brand construction chemicals in retail segment.
- Retail channel development for part of Ahmedabad, Junagadh and Kutch dist.
- Activities for market development such as mason meets, applicator trainings and branding etc.
- In depth record keeping of sales & MIS.

Date :	Place
Sign:	Ahmedabad , India